Joseph Cornell
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Source Material, 1804-1972, Series 4:; (boxes 11-18, 25-28, OV 29; 8.5 linear feet)
  - Portfolios, 1831-1957, 4.2:
    The "Ondine (Cerrito)" Portfolio represents some of the material that Cornell created and accumulated in the course of working on Portrait of Ondine, his "exploration" (or "unauthorized biography") of Fanny Cerrito and her famous role in the ballet, Ondine. Portfolio includes material, such as exhibition text and notes, relating to the exhibitions of versions of Portrait of Ondine at the Museum of Modern Art in 1946 and at the Wittenborn Bookstore in 1956 (See also Subseries 4.3); and notes indicating Cornell's desire and/or intention to present this "exploration" in another format. Portfolio also includes material on Marie Taglioni, and other material (such as a typed manuscript of Cornell's essay on Hedy Lamarr for View) that may or may not correspond to the same "exploration."
    The "Romantic Ballet" Portfolio consists of material on ballet dancers, Marie Taglioni and Tamara Toumanova, and opera singers, Maria Malibran, Pauline Viardot-Garcia, and Giuditta Pasta. It is unclear whether all the material relates directly to the Romantic Ballet "exploration," but it seems possible that Cornell was able to find linkages between Romantic and contemporary ballerinas, as well as between ballerinas and opera singers. The name of 'Gautier' inscribed on the portfolio suggests that the figure of Theophile Gautier may have been a thread linking this broad exploration. Portfolio includes material relating to a proposed "Taglioni-Poe project," which Cornell at one point intended to publish in the avant-garde periodical, Possibilities (See also the Motherwell dossier for correspondence mentioning the project); a version of his Toumanova Ballet Scrapbook and swan prints that seem to relate to the Swan Lake shadow boxes he made in tribute to her; and writings on Viardot-Garcia that trace a "Turgenev-St. Saens thread" and establish a connection between the opera singer and his box, Parrot for Juan Gris.
    Dossiers and Subject Source Files include files relating to some of the same people and topics, as well as to some of the same, or similar, projects.
    For preservation purposes, material has been removed from the original portfolio cases, which have been preserved as well. Portfolios are arranged alphabetically according to title.
    - "Ondine (Cerrito)" Portfolio, 1883, 1946-1956, undated, (2 folders, 1 item) (Box 25 (sol), Folder 1-2)
    - "Romantic Ballet" Portfolio, 1831-1957, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25 (sol), Folder 3-4)
    - "Romantic Ballet" Portfolio, 1831-1957, undated, (6 folders, 1 item) (Box 26 (sol), Folder 1-6)
  - Subject Source Files, 1804-1972, 4.3:
    Subseries is comprised of Cornell's files on various subjects, including topics of interest to him, themes, "explorations," art and publishing projects, and exhibitions. Some files are organized according to format, such as clippings, notes and writings, and stamps. Files typically consist of material that Cornell used in creating particular boxes, collages, and other works (design layouts and exhibition announcements, among others), and from which he drew ideas and inspiration for projects. Material typically includes magazine and newspaper clippings, cutouts, notes, writings, book and typed excerpts, stats, prints, postcards, art reproductions, and other printed material.
    Subject source files range from slender files containing only clippings and cutouts of a particular subject (such as Butterflies, Food, and Statues) to files of assorted printed material seemingly related to some sort of titled, but not easily identifiable, project (such as "Animals in the News," "Earth Before the Flood" Box, and "La Malaga") to voluminous files relating to a particular topic, which Cornell explored in depth, or to an on-going project, which may or may not have resulted in a finished product (such as "Celestial Theater" and "GC 44"). Some files are more comprehensive than others; some files relate directly, and others only indirectly, to particular projects; and some files are so general and/or incomplete that it is not entirely clear how they relate to Cornell's projects or interests.
    Certain subject source files relate to Cornell's "explorations" on such diverse topics as astronomy, ballet, literature, and music. Ones on astronomy include "Cassiopeia" (sparked by his musings on the constellation and his preoccupation with a young waitress) and "Celestial Theater" (an unfinished project on sky-gazing). Ones on ballet and literature include "Portrait of Ondine (Cerrito)" and the Bibliomania projects, respectively. And ones on music include "The Caliph of Bagdad" (sparked by hearing the opera by Francois-Andrien Boieldieu and leading to the creation of one or more Cockatoo boxes), "Famagouste" (inspired by the opera, "La Pisanella" by Ildebrando Pizzetti), and "Rossiniana" (involving a proposed "feuilleton-project" on the composer, Rossini).
    Other subject source files relate to particular "explorations" based on Cornell's personal experiences. Most notable among these is "GC 44," which stemmed from events during the period when he worked at the Garden Centre nursery in Flushing. The extensive "GC 44" files document the core experiences of this "exploration," which included visits to "The Old Farm" (Lawrence Homestead), a dream of "the little dancer," many trips to the "house on the hill" (where Cornell gathered dried grasses which were used in his Habitat boxes), and a particular sighting of a delivery truck "with its enseigne of the fish and smoking meats" which inspired "The Floral Still-Life" musings. Also documented are Cornell's overriding concerns to recapture and recreate what was for him "one of the high tides of inspiration" and to share the experience with others. Though he exchanged ideas and shared some of this material with others (See letter from Donald Windham to Betty Cornell Benton in Series 10), the project, as he imagined it, was never completed.
    Some subject source files relate to particular art projects and stem from Cornell's work researching, planning, and/or creating certain box constructions, box series, and collages. While by no means comprehensive or complete, files on art projects variously document the origin of certain box series (such as the Aviary and Juan Gris series) and/or stages in the development of particular boxes and collages (such as the "Nostalgia of the Sea" box, and the Rabbit and "Tina" collages). Files on art projects also suggest the way in which Cornell's preoccupations influenced his art work, as in the box, "The Bird with the Shoe-Button Eyes," which stemmed from his preoccupations with literature in general and with the French author, Gerard de Nerval, in particular and which he seems to have conceived as a means to bring the rather obscure author to the attention of a wider audience.
    Certain subject source files relate to particular publishing projects and stem from Cornell's work designing covers and illustrations, writing articles, and planning entire issues for various commercial and avant-garde periodicals (See Subseries 4.1 for his work on self-publications). Notable publishing projects documented, in part, here include "The Crystal Cage [portrait of Berenice]," and various pieces for Dance Index, including ones on "blackface ballerinas," children and ballet, and dancing animals, as well as the thematic issue, "Clowns, Elephants, and Ballerinas" (1946).
    Subject source files on exhibitions stem primarily from Cornell's work on catalogues for the "Objects by Joseph Cornell" exhibition at the Copley Gallery (September 1948), the "Night Voyage" exhibition at the Egan Gallery (February 10-March 28, 1953), and the "Romantic Museum at the Hugo Gallery: Portraits of Women" exhibition (December 1946), and they document, to a certain extent, his involvement in the presentation, exhibition, and sale of his art work.
    It is unlikely that Cornell maintained these files in alphabetical order. Betty Cornell Benton's correspondence indicates that she organized some of his papers (See Series 10), so it seems likely that this order was imposed by her. At this point, it is difficult to surmise what, if any, Cornell's original organization may have been. Therefore, files have been left in alphabetical order.
    - "1956 Scrapbook Miscellany," 1944-1956, (See Box 27) (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - "A" [Allegra Kent] File, 1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Advertisements, Turn-of-the-Century, 1887-1902, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Album Pages, undated (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - "Allegory of Faith" (painting by Giovanni Battista da Bologna), 1969, undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Ancient Art and Culture, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 47-48)
    - Animal Engravings, undated (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Animals, 1938-1960, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 50-52)
    - "Animals in the News," 1941-1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - "Anna Dream" and "Andover Dream," 1937-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
      Includes some of Cornell's dream writings and other material that may or may not relate to dreams.
    - Antiques, 1954-1967, n.d, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-6)
    - "April 30, 1961," 1961, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Architectural Drawings (German Book), 1819, (See Box 27) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Architecture, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Art Book, 1953, (see Box 27) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Art Clippings, 1953-1970, undated, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 11-12)
    - Art Collage, 1935-1964, undated, (10 folders) (Box 12, Folder 13-22)
    - Astronomy, 1953-1958, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Aviary, 1946-1949, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Ballet - Modern, Miscellaneous, 1909-1947, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Ballet - Modern, Photographs, 1944-1945, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Ballet - Romantic, Miscellaneous, 1855-1948, undated, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 27-28)
    - Ballet - Romantic, Stats, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Bibliomania - 19th-century, 1804-1944, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-32)
    - Bibliomania - 20th-century, 1839-1961, undated, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 33-34)
    - "The Bird with the Shoe-Button Eyes (for Gerard de Nerval)," 1932-1947, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Birds, 1958-1962, undated, (2 folders; see also Box 27) (Box 12, Folder 36-37)
    - "Bouteille" (Bottle) - "Pat Lewis," 1959-1965, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Box Construction (part), undated, (See OV 29) (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Box Construction Material, 1884-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 40-42)
    - Box Construction Material, 1884-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
    - "Brocehet Caroline de Gunderode" (Bracelet of Caroline von Gunderode), 1954-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - "The Bronze Statue," circa 1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Business Cards and Contact Information, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Butterflies, 1958-1962, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "The Caliph of Bagdad," 1952-1967, undated, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 9-11)
    - Cameos, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - "Cassiopeia," 1958-1966, undated, (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 13-18)
    - Cat Box, 1961-1963, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "Celestial Theater," 1871, 1944-1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 13, Folder 20-24)
    - Charity Seals, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - "Chat Emaillere" (Enamel Cat), 1964, undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Children Collage, 1949-1963, undated, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 27-28)
    - Children Cutouts, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Children's Correspondence, Class 5 St., Downtown Community School, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 30-31)
    - Children's Correspondence, Class 4-332, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Children's Correspondence, Public School 40, [1972], (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 33-34)
    - Children's Correspondence, Guest Book, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Children's Illustrations, undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Clippings, 1945-1971, n.d, (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 37-42)
    - Clippings, 1945-1971, n.d, (1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Clorinda, 1960, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Clouds, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Coffee Pot" and Memorabilia, 1966, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "Coffee Pot Schrafft's," 1971, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Collage Material, 1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Container (partial box with lid), undated, (See Box 27) (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence (See also Series 2), 1943-1972, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Corridor Store Front," undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Crafts and Industries, 1876-1945, undated, (4 folders) (Box 14, Folder 10-13)
    - "Crocus Castle," 1962-1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Dance Publications, 1929-1948, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - "Deer Nymph" (Dame Laura Knight), 1963-1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Doodlings, 1961-1972, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Drapery,undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 19-20)
    - Dutch and Flemish Art, 1924-1941, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 21-22)
    - Early Boxes, 1955-1958, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 23-25)
    - "Earth Before the Flood" Box, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Envelope Fragments, 1963, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Excerpts (from the writings of others), 1950-1956, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition, "Medici Penny Arcade Machine" ("Objects by Joseph Cornell"), 1948, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Exhibition, "Night Voyage," 1952-1953, undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition, "Romantic Museum at the Hugo Gallery: Portraits of Women," 1949-1954, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
    - Fairies, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - "Falling Star," 1964-1969, undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - "Famagouste," 1972, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Fashion, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - "Fee aux Lapins," 1958-1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 37-38)
    - Figureheads, undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Film Clippings, 1906-1946, undated (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Film Printed Material, 1944-1968, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Films, 1957-1970, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Flair Magazine, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Food, 1963, undated (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - "GC 44," Writings and Notes, 1944-1961, undated, (9 folders) (Box 14, Folder 45-53)
    - "GC 44," Writings and Notes, 1944-1961, undated, (4 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - "GC 44," Scrapbook Pages, 1944-1949, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "GC 44," Clippings, 1940-1959, undated, (15 folders) (Box 15, Folder 6-20)
    - Gitta, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Goya, 1928, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "The Grasshopper," 1970 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Greeting Cards, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Gum Collage, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Hemingway, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Heraldry, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - History, 1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - "Hotel Chariot d'Or," 1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Hummingbirds, 1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Ink Blot Drawings, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 31-32)
    - Insects, 1958-1966, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Jewelry - 19th-century, 1885-1895, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Jewelry - 20th-century, 1963-1965, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Juan Gris (Boxes), 1950-1968, undated, (9 folders) (Box 15, Folder 36-44)
    - Kress Collection (National Gallery of Art), 1952-1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Lala, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Laundresses Collage, 1965, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Lilliputian Opera, 1906, undated (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Literature, 1948-1954, undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - "La Malaga," undated (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Maps, 1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Marine Life, 1960-1963, undated (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Match Box Project, undated (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Mathematics, 1958-1970, undated, (1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Mathematics, 1958-1970, undated, (1 folder) (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Medici Prince, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Morning," "Noon," "Evening," and "Night," undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Mozart, 1951-1956, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Museum Bottles Material, 1942-1954, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Music,1953, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
    - Music, Italian Songbooks, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Music, Liner Notes, 1961, (see Box 27) (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Music, Opera Librettos, circa 1920s (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - New York, circa 1960s (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1956-1967, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "Nostalgia of the Sea," 1943-1955, undated, (3 folders) (Box 16, Folder 13-15)
    - Notes and Writings, 1941-1972, undated, (11 folders) (Box 16, Folder 16-26)
    - Notes on Making Boxes, 1957-1962, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 27-28)
    - Nudes, 1964, undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Offering" and Other Dream Writings, 1960-1964, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Office Supplies and Furniture, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Old Masters (art reproductions), undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Old Silks, undated (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Ostend, undated (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - Paperweights, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Parrot Box with Spools, undated (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - "The Peppermint Stick Monkey" (Homage to the Romantic Ballet), 1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - Photographs, Miscellaneous (See also Series 6), 1964-1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Photographs, Reproduction of "La Chanteuse Verte" by Edgar Degas, 1964-1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - Photography, 1953-1965, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - Picasso, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Pitt Magazine, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Planets, undated (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Poetry and Poets, 1949-1956, undated (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Poles, undated (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - "Portrait of Ondine (Fanny Cerrito)" (See also Subseries 4.2), 1952-1961, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 46-47)
    - "Portrait of Ondine (Fanny Cerrito)," Reproduction of Portrait by Josef Kriehuber, undated (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - "La Poupee," 1958-1963, undated (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Printed Material and Notes, Miscellaneous, 1848, 1944-1972, undated, (15 folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-15)
    - Privacy, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Publishing Project, "Americana," 1872-1952, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 17-19)
    - Publishing Project, "Clowns, Elephants, and Ballerinas," 1812-circa 1859, 1946, undated, (See Box 28) (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Publishing Project, "The Crystal Cage [portrait of Berenice]" (See also Towers), 1942-1945, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 21-22)
    - Publishing Projects, Dance Index, 1946, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Publishing Project, "Women Painters," 1855, 1948-1953, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Publishing Project, "Women Painters," Subjects, 1851, 1949-1961, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 25-26)
    - Rabbit Collage, 1954-1963, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Mlle. Raisin, 1957, undated (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Rossiniana, 1867-1954, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 29-30)
    - Science, 1953-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 31-32)
    - Script, "The Holy Ghost" by Allan Codd, 1970, (not scanned) (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Sewing, 1970, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "The Stag," 1961-1966, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Stamps, 1863-1871, 1952-1965, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Stats (photostats), undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Statues,1942-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
    - Sunsets, 1959-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - "Tina" Collage, 1965, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Towers ("The Crystal Cage [portrait of Berenice]"), undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Uccello, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Van Eyck Altarpiece, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Varia, 1947-1964, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 14-15)
    - "War Plant 1943," 1943, undated, (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 16-18)
    - "Westhampton 1952-1953," 1953-1969, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Oversized, "1956 Scrapbook Miscellany," 1944-1956, undated, (See Box 11, F42) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Architectural Drawings (German Book), 1819, (See Box 12, F8) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Art Book, 1953, (see Box 12, F10) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Birds (engraving), undated, (See Box 12, F36-37) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Container (partial box with lid), undated, (See Box 14, F7) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Music, Liner Notes, 1961, undated, (see Box 16, F9) (Box 27 (sol))
    - Oversized, Publishing Project, "Clowns, Elephants, and Ballerinas," 1812-circa 1859, 1946, undated, (3 folders; see Box 12, F20) (Box 28 (sol))
    - Oversized, Box Construction (part), undated, (See Box 12, F39) (Box OV 29)
- Ephemera and Artifacts, 1858-1946, Series 5:; (boxes 18, 23; 0.8 linear feet)
  Series consists of various items of ephemera and memorabilia, and various artifacts. Included are Victorian cards, an album of remembrance with entries by various individuals who were friends and acquaintances of the original owner, an autograph book, cartes-de-visite, dried flowers from Lawrence farm, cabinet cards (including one of Fanny Ward), hat pins, leather post cards, tobacco cards, boxes with cloth scraps and dried flowers from Ulysses S. Grant's funeral (which were mementos belonging to Cornell's grandparents), a papier-mache pull-toy horse, a shell box, sheet music, plastic dolls, match boxes, stuffed bird figures, metal pendants, clockhands, wood and cork pieces, beads, and other material. Most, if not all, of this material was accumulated by Cornell in the course of his regular collecting activities. Some of the objects are of uncertain origin and may have belonged to his brother, Robert.
  Cornell seems to have used some of these items, including the tobacco cards, sheet music, hat pins, leather post cards, cartes-de-visite, autograph book, and miniature rug samples, in a layout he designed for Good Housekeeping magazine. Other items, including the shell box, papier-mache pull-toy horse, and memento boxes from General Grant's funeral, seem to have been part of the 1982 exhibition, "Joseph Cornell: An Exploration of Sources," at the National Museum of American Art, which presented a select group of boxes and collages in the context of his source materials. (See Series 10 for a letter from the Acting Director of NMAA identifying these materials.)
  Other items in this series, such as the wood and cork pieces, the clockhands, and wooden beads, could also constitute some of the found objects that Cornell collected and often used in many of his box constructions. Items, such as dried flowers from Lawrence farm and even the memento boxes of Grant's funeral, could constitute those objects that Cornell often collected as souvenirs and memorabilia relating to a particular event or idea. The dried flowers, for instance, seem to relate to the GC 44 "exploration," of which Cornell's visits to Lawrence farm played a part.
  As far as possible, material is arranged in chronological order. For storage and preservation purposes, loose objects that cannot be housed in folders are housed together within smaller boxes, which are then housed in an archival box. For descriptive purposes, loose objects are treated as one file with an item list (provided below).
  The bulk of this series has been scanned with the exception of loose objects.
  - Album of Remembrance, 1858-1860 (Box 18, Folder 20)